<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Museum of Art and Numbers</title>
    <link>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Museum of Art and Numbers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2019, Weru and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:52:59 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Numbers and their Personalities - A Primer</title>
      <link>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/numbers-and-personalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/numbers-and-personalities/</guid>
      <description>Numbers The Greeks Developed four Liberal arts of Numbers - Astronomy, Geometry, Arithmetic and Harmony (Music). Numbers has magical properties that transcended their real-life applications.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soup Cans and Variables</title>
      <link>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/warhol-and-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/warhol-and-variables/</guid>
      <description>At some point in your mathematical education, you will reach a point where you have both numbers and letters English and Greek, and nothing is ever the same. But some all alphabets are not the same’ there are two kinds
•	Variables
•	Constants
Variables Variables are symbols which mean different things in different situations. A variable will often be dependent on another variable.
Let’s start with 2 letters, x and y.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Painting with Decimals</title>
      <link>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/decimals-and-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/decimals-and-painting/</guid>
      <description>Repetition and Non-repetition Imagine two paintings
The one on the left has a repeating pattern and is therefore predictable The one on the right has no consistent repetition wich means it is unpredictable
Terminating decimals is when you have a fractions whose expansion is simple
How is this Relevant to Decimal expansions? e.g – $\frac{1}{2} = 0.50000$ or $\frac{12}{50} = 0.240000$
Sometime it gets harder and the extension never ends</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi with the vitruvian man</title>
      <link>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/pi-and-the-vitruvian-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/pi-and-the-vitruvian-man/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The symbol Pi may strike fear in the hearts of some people, but its basic function is simple, to calculate the sizes of round things.
•	Nasa uses Pi to calculate the size of planets outside our solar system.•	GPS uses pi to calculate location on earth•	Medical Researchers use pi t study the structure of the eye. Pi describes how long the border (circumference) of a circle is, compared to its height (diameter) So, if the diameter of a circle is 1, the border of a circle is Pi</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travelling with Exponents</title>
      <link>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/exponents-and-st.-ives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/exponents-and-st.-ives/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A Classic English poem reads:
&amp;ldquo;As I went to St Ives
I met Nine Wives
And every Wife had nine Sacs,
And every Sac had nine Cats
And every Cat had nine Kittens&amp;rdquo;
Each a each level you multiply the exponents by the number nine
Let&amp;rsquo;s look at how this works
At each level the exponent is increased by multiplying 9 again.
At each level you multiply the exponents by the number nine</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forbidden Love and Common Multiples</title>
      <link>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/lcm-romeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/lcm-romeo/</guid>
      <description>What are Factors and Multiples A factor is simply a number that fits into another In the above images, you can see that 2, 3 and 6, all fit into the number 6
A Multiple, is a number that can be produced by multiplying a number. In the above image, you can see that 2, 4, 6 and 8 are all multiples of 2
Prime factors The prime factors of a number allow you to break a number into its most basic pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Factors and pretty tiles</title>
      <link>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/hcf-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/hcf-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Tiles are based on Patterns of smaller components fitting into a bigger space
If you take a rectangular space, only a certain number of full-sized tiles will be able to fit into it.
Let’s take Two variables, A and B (A has to be greater or equal to B) Suppose you have the Numbers 39 and 15 15 fits two times into 39, and you still have 9 left over</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gallery of Mathematical Curiosities</title>
      <link>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/post/gallery/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Greeks beleived that all numbers were rational. They
hippasus argument </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo</title>
      <link>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cerulean-cactus-9432fc.netlify.app/about/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is the world’s fastest framework for building websites. It is written in Go.
It makes use of a variety of open source projects including:
 https://github.com/russross/blackfriday https://github.com/alecthomas/chroma https://github.com/muesli/smartcrop https://github.com/spf13/cobra https://github.com/spf13/viper  Learn more and contribute on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
